Great job so far!
You've done a comprehensive analysis of the attributes in our
dataset and generated many interesting insights for the HealthStat team.
In this chapter, we will focus our efforts on putting the key elements together into a cohesive dashboard.
We will finish things off by optimizing the design and adding report navigation features.
Throughout this case study, our focus has been on measuring efficiency in hospitals,
which, as we discussed previously, is one of the six dimensions in healthcare quality.
We started with analyzing average LOS days and then added in the calculation of average cost per discharge.
Hospital management continually strives to reduce LOS and costs where possible
so as to maximize efficiency while not compromising the quality of patient care.
These are the insight themes we will be focusing on for the final dashboard product.
In our quest to analyze efficiency in hospitals across New York State, we found the average cost per discharge
for a hip replacement surgery was $21K, and that there was significant variability between hospital facilities.
Our root cause analysis found that some attributes stood out over others to influence both cost and average LOS.
Patients who had an extreme illness severity, and extreme or major
mortality risk stood out as having the most significant impact on reduced efficiency.
Also, hospitals located in New York City tended to have a higher cost and LOS
overall, and lastly, that LOS was influenced by patient disposition to a skilled nursing home.
These insights are very useful and will help HealthStat to inform improvement initiatives for their clients.
In this final chapter, we will work on building a report that provides concise insight to our stakeholders.
We will produce a clean, branded design that showcases the most important insights uncovered.
Here is a preview of some of the report components and contents.
Let's get back to it!